A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Provision law and specific tax records, 1779-1797
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Provision law and specific tax records, 1779-1797
The Library of Virginia
APA 640
1.15 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts (1776-1928)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Auditor of Public Accounts in 1913.
Biographical Information
During its session begun in May 1780 the General Assembly passed an act authorizing the governor to appoint a commissioner for each county to purchase or impress goods and services for military use. Receipts or certificates were given by the commissioners to persons whose property was impressed, and the certificates could be used for the payment of taxes. In October 1780 the provision law was renewed and amended to require the commissioners to be bonded on entering office.
During its session begun in May 1779 the General Assembly passed an act for the defense of the commonwealth that placed a specific tax on every male above sixteen years old and every female slave above sixteen years. Bacon was added to the list of commodities with which the tax could be paid. The commissioners made returns of accounts to the county court and the governor, and sent the auditor a list of unpaid balances to be collected by the sheriff.
Scope and Content
Records, 1779-1797, including accounts, bonds, and correspondence. The accounts contain the names of persons to whom payments were made, the amounts, and the dates paid. Each bond contains the signatures of the claimant and securities, the date, and the amount of the bond.
These records are part of Auditor of Public Accounts. Administration of State Government: Revenue Assessment and Collection - Specific Taxes.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title with oversize materials arranged to the rear.
Contents List
- Albemarle County, 1780-1783. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Amelia County, 1782. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Amherst County, 1780-1783. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Augusta County, 1779-1797. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bedford County, 1782. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Berkeley County, 1781. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Botetourt County, 1780-1784. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brunswick County, 1782-1786. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Buckingham County, 1781-1783. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Campbell County, 1782-1783. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Caroline County, 1780-1783. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Charles City County, 1781-1784. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Charlotte County, 1780-1787. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Chesterfield County, 1780. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Culpeper County, 1780-1783. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cumberland County, 1781-1783. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Dinwiddie County, 1782-1784. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Elizabeth City County, 1782. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Essex County, 1780-1789. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Fairfax County, 1780-1790. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Fauquier County, 1781-1786. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Frederick County, 1780-1790. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Fluvanna County, 1781-1783. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Gloucester County, 1781-1789. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Goochland County, 1780-1787. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Greenbrier County, 1782. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Greensville County, 1781-1782. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Halifax County, 1782-1786. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Hampshire County, 1781-1784. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Hanover County, 1780-1786. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Henrico County, 1782-1785. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Henry County, 1782-1783. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Isle of Wight County, 1782-1785. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- James City County, 1782. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- King and Queen County, 1781-1784. (Box 1, Folder 35)
- King George County, 1781-1782. (Box 1, Folder 36)
- King William County, 1781-1789. (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Lancaster County, 1781-1782. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Loudon County, 1781-1786. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Louisa County, 1780-1786. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lunenburg County, 1781-1783. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Mecklenburg County, 1781-1785. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Middlesex County, 1781-1782. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Montgomery County, 1782. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Nansemond County, 1782. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- New Kent County, 1782-1783. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Norfolk County, 1782-1786. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Northampton County, undated. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Northumberland County, 1781-1782. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Orange County, 1781-1783. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Pittsylvania County, 1782-1783. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Powhatan County, 1782-1784. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Prince Edward County, 1781-1784. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Prince George County, 1780-1784. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Prince William County, 1781-1782. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Richmond County, 1781-1782. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Rockbridge County, 1780-1789. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Rockingham County, 1782-1783. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Shenandoah County, 1781-1785. (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Southampton County, 1780-1785. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Spotsylvania County, 1781-1789. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Stafford County, 1782. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Surry County, 1781-1786. (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Sussex County, 1780-1783. (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Warwick County, 1783-1785. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Washington County, 1782-1784. (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Westmoreland County, 1780-1783. (Box 2, Folder 30)
- York County, 1780-1784. (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Accounts, 1781-1782. (Box 2, Folder 32)
- List of Taxes Received from Various Counties, 1782. (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Voucher, 1781-1782. (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Caroline County (oversize), 1781. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- James City County-Williamsburg (oversize), 1782-1783. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- King William County (oversize), 1780. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Louisa County (oversize), 1781. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Mecklenburg County (oversize), 1781. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- New Kent County (oversize), 1781. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Westmoreland County (oversize), 1780-1781. (Box 3, Folder 7)